<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science on Johnny&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/categories/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science on Johnny&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The best of the EFL (for your FPL)</title>
      <link>/2020/08/22/the-best-of-the-efl-for-your-fpl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/08/22/the-best-of-the-efl-for-your-fpl/</guid>
      <description>If the EFL championship could be summed up in one way it would be Gerhard Struber&#39;s interview on the final day of the season when his side, Barnsley, managed a dramatic win in the 91st minute over automatic promotion contenders Brentford to secure their place in the EFL championship next season.
If you haven&#39;t watched this already, you need to:
Watch the full length post-match interview with a teary eyed Gerhard Struber following @BarnsleyFc’s great escape!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Words are viral too</title>
      <link>/2020/05/09/words-are-viral-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/09/words-are-viral-too/</guid>
      <description>On the 9 January 2020, the New York Times published an article with the following headline,
 ‘China Identifies New Virus Causing Pneumonialike Illness’
 Little did we know back then the scale of the pandemic that awaited us. Hauntingly, the article was prefaced with a statment that there was ‘no evidence of human-to-human transmission’. Alert levels were low.
But then, just 11 days later on the 20 January 2020, a new article was published which confirmed our worst fears,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The evolution of the Tour De France</title>
      <link>/2020/04/12/the-evolution-of-the-tour-de-france/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/04/12/the-evolution-of-the-tour-de-france/</guid>
      <description>The Dreyfus affair  “I swear that I am innocent. I remain worthy of serving in the Army. Long live France! Long live the Army!”
 These were the famous words uttered by Alfred Dreyfus as he was convicted by fellow French officials in a secret court martial back in 1895, following allegations of espionage and treason against the French state. The incident - commonly referred to as the ‘Dreyfus affair’ - went down as one of the most controversial and polarising political dramas in all of French history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why your password sucks</title>
      <link>/2020/01/27/why-your-password-sucks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/27/why-your-password-sucks/</guid>
      <description>A story about ‘Steve’  “Steve is very shy and withdrawn, invariably helpful but with little interest in people or in the world of reality. A meek and tidy soul, he has a need for order and structure, and a passion for detail.”
 In his seminal work, “Thinking Fast and Slow”, Daniel Kahneman - referring to this short description - poses the following question: is Steve more likely to be a librarian or a farmer?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>