<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Johnny&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Johnny&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Words are viral too</title>
      <link>/2020/05/09/words-are-viral-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/09/words-are-viral-too/</guid>
      <description>On the 9 January 2020, the New York Times published an article with the following headline,
 ‘China Identifies New Virus Causing Pneumonialike Illness’
 Little did we know back then the scale of the pandemic that awaited us. Hauntingly, the article was prefaced with a statment that there was ‘no evidence of human-to-human transmission’. Alert levels were low.
But then, just 11 days later on the 20 January 2020, a new article was published which confirmed our worst fears,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The evolution of the Tour De France</title>
      <link>/2020/04/12/the-evolution-of-the-tour-de-france/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/04/12/the-evolution-of-the-tour-de-france/</guid>
      <description>The Dreyfus affair  “I swear that I am innocent. I remain worthy of serving in the Army. Long live France! Long live the Army!”
 These were the famous words uttered by Alfred Dreyfus as he was convicted by fellow French officials in a secret court martial back in 1895, following allegations of espionage and treason against the French state. The incident - commonly referred to as the ‘Dreyfus affair’ - went down as one of the most controversial and polarising political dramas in all of French history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The perils of medical testing</title>
      <link>/2020/03/29/the-perils-of-medical-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/03/29/the-perils-of-medical-testing/</guid>
      <description>You’ve been feeling under the weather for more than a couple of days and things don’t seem to be improving. So, you pluck up the courage to call your local doctor. He tells you that it’s probably just an innocuous virus but he decides to run a series of remote tests on you regardless, ‘just to be safe’.
The next day you receive your results: your doctor informs you that you have tested positive for a very serious disease that only affects approximately 5% of the global population.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why your password sucks</title>
      <link>/2020/01/27/why-your-password-sucks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/27/why-your-password-sucks/</guid>
      <description>A story about ‘Steve’  “Steve is very shy and withdrawn, invariably helpful but with little interest in people or in the world of reality. A meek and tidy soul, he has a need for order and structure, and a passion for detail.”
 In his seminal work, “Thinking Fast and Slow”, Daniel Kahneman - referring to this short description - poses the following question: is Steve more likely to be a librarian or a farmer?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Johnny Breen and I currently work as an actuarial consultant in London.
I started this blog after being inspired by David Robinson&amp;rsquo;s excellent presentation at the 2019 R Studio Conference, where he discussed the importance of sharing one&amp;rsquo;s own work.
The object of the blog is statistical analysis but anyone is welcome to read. Topics are presented at a high level and those who are interested in reading the underlying code can do so by referring to my GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>