<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Johnny&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Johnny&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Captive Cetaceans - Mortality Investigation</title>
      <link>/2019/03/30/captive-cetaceans-mortality-investigation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/03/30/captive-cetaceans-mortality-investigation/</guid>
      <description>Introduction So, here it is: my first ever contribution to the TidyTuesday project hosted on github! In this post, I am going to analyse a dataset on various cetacean species, originally analysed by Amber Thomas in an excellent Pudding article. Although this dataset is a less recent submission, I chose it because I was interested to learn a bit about the history of cetacean captivity and also their potential future in the context of climate risk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trump Tweets - Exploratory Analysis</title>
      <link>/2019/03/16/exploratory-analysis-of-trump-tweets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/03/16/exploratory-analysis-of-trump-tweets/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The data that I have chosen to analyse in this document is a repository of Trump tweets which span roughly two years of data all the way up until Trump’s election as US president in November 2016. The original CSV file I have used in the following analysis can be found here on Kaggle.
 Credits My analysis of Trump’s tweets draws a substantial amount of insight from David Robinson’s recent screencast where he analysed a repository of medium articles - that specific screencast can be found here and I highly encourage anyone interested in text mining to watch it at their next available moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Johnny Breen and I currently work as an actuarial consultant in London - for those unaware of what this job entails, I refer you to this gem.
I started this blog after coming across David Robinson&amp;rsquo;s excellent presentation at the 2019 R Studio Conference, where he explained the - perhaps underestimated - value of making your work public. Indeed, the presentation made me realise that you lose out by not sharing your work with others: recognition and constructive criticism of your work are both crucial.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>